JAVY DE KONING, MSc.

■ JAVYDEKONING@GMAIL.COM ■ (+31)6-204 735 02

NOVEMBER 6TH, 1986

BOS EN LOMMERPLNTS. 97H · 1055AA · AMSTERDAM (THE NETHERLANDS)

JAVYDEKONING GITHUB.COM/JAVYDEKONING/ LINKEDIN.COM/IN/JAVYDEKONING

Professional Summary

A business focused and forward thinking team leader who's able to set a motivating environment that gives staff a sense of pride in their work. Over 10 years of hands-on experience in designing, maintaining and supporting enterprise sized IT infrastructures. Special interest in automation, configuration management and devops. Loves PowerShell, DSC, Nano Server, Docker and most bleeding edge IT technology.

Relevant Professional Experience

Employer	IPsoft	Amsterdam, The Netherlands
Job Title	Technical Executive, Team Supervisor Windows	May 2015 — now
Reference	Nick Walsh	

IPsoft is a managed service provider, pioneering innovation in the development and delivery of autonomic and cognitive technologies. For IPsoft I'm tasked with a dual role. In the position of Team-Supervisor I'm overseeing the quality of employee performance and creating a motivating workplace. I was also be directly involved with interviewing and hiring of employees.

Key Contributions:

- Leading a team of eight Senior IT engineers and two Junior IT engineers.
- Overseeing the on-boarding training curriculum.
- Conducted over 50 technical job interviews.
- Grew the team from three to ten IT engineers over one year.
- Setup a quarterly in-house automation training.
- Manage relationships to ensure employee satisfaction.
- Created KPI's providing management with input about the performance of members of the team.

In the position of Technical Executive I am responsible for running the day to day IT operations for one of our top clients. Ensuring the organization's IT technology works efficiently and securely, which is the main goal. The global, multi-site IT environment consists of over 1000 Windows and Linux/Unix servers running on top of 80 plus VMware vSphere/ESXi hosts.

Key Contributions:

- Leading a team of 7 Senior IT engineers by training, motivating and setting clear objectives.
- Building a strong trust and positive relationship with the client.
- Written over 50 SOP's to ensure uniform effective processing of requests and incidents.
- Oversee all technical projects, system and software upgrades.
- Building a weekly automation pipeline ensuring maximum autonomic resolution for the client.
- Manage relationships with (third party) vendors for technical products and services for the organization.
- Hosting bi-weekly internal team meetings.

Employer	IPsoft	Amsterdam, The Netherlands
Job Title	Technical Lead, Sr. Windows Engineer	November 2014 — April 2015
References	Michell Grauwmans, Remco Veltrop	

Key Contributions:

- Diagnosed and re-mediated issues within enterprise sized Windows Server Infrastructure's.
- Build and bug-fix over a hundred automatons which either diagnose or completely resolve recurring issues saving my employer many FTE's. Used technologies include PowerShell, Bash, SQL and JavaScript.
- Worked with tier 1 clients to align and support their requirements with a high level of attention and intimacy.
- Develop automation using PowerShell and JavaScript to automate repetitive tasks in the client environments.
- Lead technical projects and deployments improving the client's infrastructure.

Employer	Nederlandse Spoorwegen	Utrecht, The Netherlands
Job Title	Active Directory consultant	October 2013 — October 2014
Reference	John de Mol	

NS provides rail services on the Dutch main rail network (hoofdrailnet). 25,000 employees make sure that 4,800 domestic trains run every day. I was hired as an Active Directory consultant to inventory, migrate, clean and decommission Active Directory domains.

Key Contributions:

- Decommissioned eight Active Directory domains to improve security, reliability and reduce the complexity of the Active Directory domain infrastructure.
- Automated repetitive Active Directory inventory reports using Microsoft PowerShell, saving my employer 2 FTE's.
- Developed a tool using PowerShell to detect network and firewall issues between domain controllers across multiple forests.
- Designed and implemented an Active Directory housekeeping policy to ensure a secure and healthy domain environment.
- Identified and resolved several LAN and DNS connectivity issues.
- Consolidated user, computer and group objects across four primary Active Directory domains.
- Managed Active Directory operations and resolved weekly third-tier technical task tickets using HP Operations Manager.

Employer	Em'bed	Den Haag, The Netherlands
Job Title	Infrastructure specialist	September 2013 — October 2014
Reference	Maurits van Boetzelaer	

Em'bed is a consultancy firm specializing in identity and access management solutions. In the position of Infrastructure specialist I performed several Active Directory security and health assessments.

Key Contributions:

- Developed an automated Active Directory and Exchange assessment tool using PowerShell v2.
- Identified and reported several Active Directory configuration issues for multiple clients.

Employer	Meritor, Inc	Roermond, The Netherlands
Job Title	Windows engineer	May 2011 — September 2012
Reference	Martijn Tigchelaar	

Meritor, Inc. is a corporation headquartered in Troy, Michigan (USA) which manufactures automobile components for light service vehicles, trucks, and trailers. Meritor is a Fortune 500 company that has 9,000 employees in 18 countries. I was responsible for providing Windows and VMware administration. Also managed network monitoring servers, Active Directory, DNS, Exchange, WSUS and wireless access points (Radius).

Key Contributions:

- Designed, implemented, and maintained the new Active Directory domain infrastructure supporting 9,000 users.
- Replaced 50+ Windows 2000 domain controllers with Windows 2003 and Windows 2008R2 domain controllers
- Migrated DNS, WINS, DHCP, IAS and WSUS services from Windows 2000 servers to new VM's running Windows 2008R2.
- Managed data center operations and resolved ten daily third-tier technical support tickets using Remedy.
- Managed, Deployed and maintained 30+ private virtual clouds based on VMWare vSphere 5.0 vCenter v5.0.

EDUCATION

University	The University of Amsterdam	Amsterdam, The Netherlands
Degree	Master of Science in Computer Science	September 2012 — July 2013

SNE is the University of Amsterdam master education in System and Network Engineering. SNE focuses on Open Standards, Open Software and Open Security, hence the name OS3. A large part of the education focuses on the security of systems and networks.

University	Hogeschool Zuyd	Heerlen, The Netherlands
Degree	Bachelor of Science in Computer Science	August 2008 — September 2010

Bachelor education in Network and Infrastructure Design. The education focused on IT Services, IT Development and Business Intelligence. Also provided hands-on experience using Microsoft and Cisco products.

SURFNET BGP Origin Validation (RPKI)

June 2013

The goal is to increase the adoption rate of RPKI. Hence we've build SURFnet's RPKI Dashboard, which provides network operators with a number of RPKI statistics and assists them in cleaning up possible invalid prefixes.

https://labs.ripe.net/Members/javy_de_koning/rpki-dashboard http://goo.gl/bwOxjD

NLNET LABS Defending against DNS reflection amplification attacks

February 2013

The goal of the research was to find out if the proposed mechanisms to defend against a DNS amplification attacks are effective. The main conclusion is that response rate limiting is a proper defense mechanism against current amplification attacks, but it is not effective against more sophisticated attacks. Attacks. http://goo.gl/ywn9vS

UVA Security in mobile banking

December 2012

The goal of the research was to find out how the security used in Android based mobile banking applications is implemented. During this project we discovered a serious weakness in the ABN AMRO mobile banking Android app which was exposing PIN and transaction information. Attp://goo.gl/P66Xvn

HIGHLIGHTS OF IT SKILLS

Languages Fluent in PowerShell, PowerCli and DSC. Good knowledge about JavaScript. Average

knowledge about Bash/Shell scripting and SQL.

Microsoft Azure, Containers, Active Directory, DFS, IIS, SCCM, WSUS, DNS, DHCP,

Virtualization Docker, VMware (ESXi, vCenter), Hyper-V

Others GIT, Pester (Unit testing), DSC (Configuration management)

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft MCSE 2012 (2014), MCITP: Virtualization Administrator (2011)

VMWare VCP5-DCV (2012)

EC-Council Certified Ethical Hacker (2014)

Others ITILv3: Foundation (2014), PRINCE2: Foundation, Business Information Management

(BISL, 2014)

INTERESTS AND HOBBIES

Sports Early morning fitness is the best way to exercise for me. I feel it is a great way to get

motivated in the morning, it also brings a lot of energy.

Travel Frequently organize city-trips with a group of friends. Travelled through Asia together

with my girlfriend.

Reading Love to motivate myself by reading or listen to business or self-improvement (au-

dio)books.

Technology Frequent attendee to tech-talks, conferences and meet-ups. Co-organised monthly meet-

ups and helped organising PowerShell Saturday.